Nice job, boys!
They were all so antsy during the opening ceremonies, but I don't think they look as nervous as they did during yesterday's practice.
Right. Right. Okay, I got it. Thanks for that.
Who was that, coach?
Again!
Shimera from the Tokyo Metropolitan Gym.
It seems the matches are moving faster than expected.
It's really important to get warmed up properly, especially in the beginning.
I was hoping we'd have more time to do that.
It's about ten minutes to the Tokyo Metropolitan Gymnasium by bus.
Hey, guys! Time to get going!
Sir!
Yeah!
Mom, I have to go pee!
Well, hurry up and go!
Mm-hmm.
Oh, there, there. I know you're hungry.
How long until the next bus?
Four minutes.
Potty time!
I'm gonna go, too.
I can stay here and watch your stuff.
Thank you.
Thus foreshadowing missing the bus.
Hey! Stop that!
You first years have a lot of equipment.
Can I help you carry some of it?
No, no, that's okay.
These nerves are gonna kill me if I don't keep busy with something.
No problem.
All right. Just stay calm.
Daiichi, you do know you're talking to yourself, right?
Shut up, man.
Asahi, you forgot your access pass.
Oh, sorry about that.
Remember, they aren't going to let you in if you don't have this on you, okay?
Everyone's still pretty stiff, but it's nothing I didn't expect.
And now I need to calm down.
Huh?
What's wrong? Think you forgot something?
No, it's this bag.
It looks like mine, but it's not mine.
Huh?
Uh...
My shoes were in it.
They're gone!
We'll be right back.
It's mine!
Okay, calm down, you two.
I'm just going to call the gym where we were doing our warm-ups.
Should we go and buy some new ones?
If it comes down to that, we'll have to.
I'm so sorry!
It's okay, guys.
Nobody's dying.
Hey, man.
Where's your phone?
It's inside that bag!
You're brilliant, Kageyama!
Hello?
Well, apparently no one over there has turned in a bag yet.
I just found out that it was some kid that accidentally took it.
His mom says they'll wait for us at the gym.
Oh, thank goodness.
It's still close.
Yeah, but you forget that Shimura took the bus and went back home to pick up the crew from the neighborhood.
I'll do it.
I can go pick them up.
I should probably be the one to go.
It's fine.
I have the speed and stamina to get there and back.
Besides, I won't always be around.
And I know you'll feel kind of lost without me next year.
So now's the time for you to get started.
Right.
I promise he'll be back before the match starts.
We're so sorry!
This is probably too much, but try not to worry while I'm gone.
Thanks, Kyoko.
We're counting on you.
Dear Kyoko, run like the beautiful and bouncy wind.
It kind of makes me feel uncomfortable when you guys talk like that, so please don't.
Come on, guys.
This is Kyoko.
She'll be fine.
Right.
That's done.
Let's concentrate on our match.
We need to get down there and get warmed up.
Yes, sir!
After practicing and practicing and practicing,
everything I had worked so hard for was over, just like that.
What did I do differently at that time?
I could feel my stride, my legs cutting through the air.
But then, they hit something.
Something hard.
And my heart, it felt like it just stopped.
Got this!
One more lap!
Kyoko, have you joined the club yet?
I think you'd make a great volleyball manager.
Maybe it was just that somehow the fact scared me, even more than I realized.
Sure.
The volleyball team hadn't had a manager for a long time, so I had to figure out a lot of
it on my own.
The rules of the game, the referee's hand signals, how points were scored.
It felt good to devote myself to something, but part of me still felt like I was on the outside, and it was a relief to know that I wasn't out there on the front lines.
But as time went on, gradually, the boys on the team stopped feeling like strangers to me.
Listen up.
The floors here will be much harder to slide on.
They're not like the wooden floors you're all used to.
If you dive at the floor like usual, you'll get hurt.
Use your sweat to get rid of some friction.
Yes, sir!
Thank you very much!
Right!
Go!
Yeah!
That high ceiling's probably gonna cause more trouble than I bargained for.
Huh?
It's our first time playing in this arena, and it's enormous.
We're just gonna have to accept that it's gonna take them some time to get a good feel for all that space.
Hit the ball higher than usual!
Yes, sir!
It's so bright!
Ah!
Come on!
Gotta start paying attention!
All right!
Oh, man.
It takes me forever to get my hands to warm up whenever I'm really nervous.
Do you think you'll need some gloves?
Uh, no.
I'll be good.
So don't you ever get nervous, Kageyama?
I do.
But not right now.
Well, why not?
This is just another step forward.
Hey!
It doesn't answer my question!
Uh...
Come on, shoes!
Hurry up already!
Okay!
The team manager job.
I just kind of took it on a whim.
The position had been empty before I showed up.
So I figured, once I left, it would just go back to how it was.
But now...
Now things are different.
Now I need to pass the torch.
There's someone else who's going to need it.
After practicing, and practicing, and practicing, and practicing, everything you worked for ends so much faster than you ever expected.
But so what?
This doesn't mean I'm convinced we'll lose.
This doesn't mean I'm convinced we'll win.
I won't be standing on that court.
I won't even be wearing the uniform.
But right now...
I have to take on this challenge.
For me, right now...
This is the front lines.
I've got the shoes!
You did it, Kyoko!
I'm so sorry!
I think I can jump about five meters now!
Oh?
I cannot wait to see that.
Hey!
Line up, guys!
We are...
FUN!
Yeah!
My freaking nerves are about to kill me.
So let's at least make sure that everyone can hear us out there.
Come on.
Don't make it sound like the only thing we know how to do is yell really loud.
Ladies and gentlemen, we have Karasuno High School versus the squad of Tsubakihara Academy.
Let the game begin!
Let's play!
Frankly, considering how nervous everyone was, I was pretty worried earlier.
But they seem to have recovered nicely.
Yeah, Hinata in particular.
Maybe his losing his shoes was actually something of a blessing.
We can thank Kyoko for making sure it wasn't a nightmare.
Yeah!
You doing okay, Maruyama?
Looks to me like you have some bad performance anxiety.
Uh-huh.
I'm okay, sir.
We were back home before I knew it last year.
And I'm not repeating that nightmare again.
Yeah, you were a total wreck last year at our first championship.
Let's focus up here, boys.
Remember to use your serves to divide up their attacks.
If we don't give him a lot of places to send the ball, we can take them.
But don't take your eyes off their number 10.
He'll hit the ball from where we're least expecting it.
Yes, sir!
They're totally staring at us.
That's the team that ended up knocking Shiratorizawa out last fall, isn't it?
I'd say we just try not to think about that.
And I'd say you'd rather be playing Shiratorizawa now?
Uh-huh.
Oh, hell no.
Right.
We watched their qualifiers game, and it's not like they were able to crush Shiratorizawa or anything.
Always remember, there is such a thing as a lucky break.
Hmm.
Oh!
We're lucky we're not playing Ushiwaka.
Exactly.
You always know how to push the young guys and take their thinking in a positive direction.
Of course.
It doesn't change the fact that those guys did beat Shiratorizawa.
But that, that's not going to matter much anymore.
Maru's not the only player on this team who regrets last year.
Every team here has defeated one powerhouse school or another to qualify.
And these powerhouse beating powerhouses may still disappear in the blink of an eye.
And in this first match, the team that gets swallowed up by their opponents, by the stadium, is the one that disappears.
Hit him with a killer serve!
That's out!
Good eye!
I'm sorry, everyone.
It's fine.
I'm going to get the next one.
Smoky hide, do or die!
Sorry!
Cover!
He deliberately served it right where the back row setter would have to cross somebody's path.
He hit it to the worst possible spot like it was nothing.
Taiji!
Nice receive!
One guy we have to look out for is number four, Tera Domari.
He's 190 centimeters tall and can hit the ball even with a bad set.
His attacks from the back row are pretty intense, too.
So you do whatever you can to make sure he doesn't get over your block.
It's yours!
Chess! Cover!
Tanaka!
Too long.
Nice kill!
Sorry, guys.
It's okay. Keep it going.
Got it!
Here he comes.
Number 10.
Chabaki high! Do or die! Chabaki high! Do or die! Chabaki high!
In volleyball, the ball is almost constantly in the air.
A sharp sense of spatial awareness is absolutely essential.
But right now, they're nervous.
And they've never played in this gym before.
Those two factors are definitely throwing off that spatial awareness.
And I suspect there's one thing that's been affected most by this new environment.
The usually perfect precision of Kageyama's sets.
I'll get there, but I'll need a little more time.
Yeah, I know.
It's too long.
Kageyama's still adapting.
We have to hold on until he figures it out.
Well, Joe, you can definitely tell that Kurasuno High School is a bit stiff.
Yes, it's rare to see Kageyama make such obvious mistakes.
It's really hurting us that we weren't able to let Kageyama and Hinata practice together in this building.
Teratomari drops the ball right into Kurasuno's midcourt.
He's got a good eye.
And with that, Tsubaki Hara pulls ahead.
Kurasuno's setter is definitely off his game.
Let's bait him.
Their quick's not coming.
Just keep to the left side.
It's not?
I thought it was next.
Got it!
Oh, yeah, guys, way to go!
Keep it up!
Damn it.
He went for the left anyway.
I tried to bait him, but they baited me instead.
Okay.
That one was about half a ball too short.
Hmm.
Too high.
Damn these guys.
They've got miracle shots now?
We're fine.
Freak accident.
Let's just move on.
What was that?
It was awesome!
I'm almost there.
No matter how much you tell yourself it's okay and that you can catch up, the panic will
still get to you.
But if you let it swallow you, it's over.
And that's why we're going to give them an early boost.
Look at that.
Yeah, he's throwing Tadashi in there pretty early today.
In this tournament, I'm probably only going on the court to serve.
That's why I've replayed this scenario hundreds of times in my head.
Listen up, Tadashi.
Tadashi.
Don't wait for your nerves to settle on their own.
You need to practice calming them yourself.
And the most effective way for you to do that is finding a reset point.
Uh-huh.
The first thing to do, when you're warming up, look for a spot you can focus on.
It can be anything that won't move, like a poster or a logo or the lights of an emergency
exit.
For now, we're just going to use that bag over there.
First, I reset my emotions.
Then I take aim.
My target is the spot behind their ace.
To hit it there, I have to send the ball over the right part of the net.
It's going towards their libero.
Damn, I hesitated.
We threw him off.
That's you go.
Finish it.
Three blockers.
Nice one.
First block of the day.
Receivers.
You need to make up your minds faster.
Yes, sir.
Tanashi, serve up a good one.
Yeah!
Yes, yes, yes!
How much did that kid improve?
It hasn't even been that long.
One more!
My go!
Got it!
Tsubakihara has just ended Karasuno's run.
But it does look like Karasuno is finally gaining some momentum, Joe.
All right, let's keep going into those double digits.
Yeah!
Tsukishiba!
Nice kill, Tsuki!
Tsuki!
Yes!
Nice job out there!
Keep it going, boys!
But still, we can't seem to close the gap.
Okay, I think I got it.
To me.
Come on, send it my way.
Send it to me.
Give it to me.
I want it.
Come on.
Give it to me.
Yeah!
I bet if Hinata ever gets scared of messing up, he just pushes that feeling aside.
And, well, it seems to be working.
Boom.
Perfection.
I'm there.
Sorry it took so long.
Take it.
Thank you.
Next time, a chance to keep it going.